Finding Aid for William Albright Papers 1962-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Scores
  - Various Composers
    - Ferko, Frank
      - A Practical Program for Monks: For Tenor Voice and Organ (by Thomas Merton), copyright, 1990 (Box 33)
    - Ferneyhough, Brian
      - Funerailles: Seven Strings and Harp, 1980 (Box 33)
    - Fields, Matthew (student)
      - Arbor Nocturne for Camerata Vassileva, copyright, 1998 (Box 33)
      - Call of the Shofar for four trombones, copyright, 1992 (Box 33)
      - Crossroads for high voice and seven players (by A.J. Cannaday), copyright, 1994 (Box 33)
      - Kabala, copyright, 1993 (Box 33)
      - Rooster's Court Ball: six movements for flute, copyright, 1993 (Box 33)
        (includes note from composer and c.v.)
      - Sh'mah for carillon, copyright, 1995 (Box 33)
      - String Quartet No.1: Three Origami Figures, copyright, 1991 (Box 33)
      - Summer Mischief for harpsichord, copyright, 1993 (Box 33)
      - The Winds of Springtime for pianoforte, 1990 (Box 33)
      - Winter Moonbronze: Carillon, 1992 (Box 33)
    - Finney, Ross Lee (teacher)
      - Chamber Music: High Voice and Piano, 1952 (Box 34)
      - Chaucer's Nun's Priest's Tale for Solo voices, chorus and chamber orchestra, copyright, 1965 (Box 34)
      - Three Love Songs to Words by John Donne, copyright, 1957 (Box 34)
      - Three Pieces: Strings Winds, Percussion and Tape, 1962 (Box 34)
      - Weep Torn Land: An Opera in Seven Scenes undated (Box 34)
    - Flippo, David
      - Danza del Dragone for 5-octave Marimba or 2-manual Harpsichord, 1984 (Box 34)
    - Friedl, Reinhold
      - Russische Dichtung, 1980 (Box 34)
    - Foley, David (student)
      - Memorabilia (Seven Pieces for Piano Solo), undated (Box 34)
      - Wishes for SATB, copyright, 1968 (Box 34)
    - Fortner, Jack (friend)
      - Chart, undated (Box 50)
      - Emily Dickinson: female voice and piano, 1982 (Box 34)
      - Flow Chart I--Apres Jonas 5:5, 1974 (Box 34)
      - Fur Eloisa, 1993 (Box 34)
      - Sonnets, 1994 (Box 34)
      - Trois Gymnopedies, 1990 (Box 34)
    - French, Tania Gabrielle
      - Equinox for String Quartet, circa 1993 (Box 34)
      - Sacred Journey: Concerto for Violin and Orchestra undated (Box 34)
        (first movement only)
    - Freudenthaler, Erland M. (student)
      - Amadeus Rag for Piano, 1992 (Box 34)
      - Bobby Rag for Piano, 1992 (Box 34)
      - Call and Response for Carillon, 1991 (Box 34)
      - Concertino & Fuge: Konzert fur violine & streichorchester, 1991 (Box 34)
      - Ein Mensch, op.4: ein stuck fur klavier und metronom, 1984 (Box 34)
      - Fata Morgana (Repetition contra Reflexion) fur 12 Saxophone & Schlagwerk, 1990 (Box 34)
      - 5 Charakterstucke fur Klavier, 1989 (Box 34)
      - 5 Farcical Rags for Piano 1992 (Box 34)
      - Flibbertigibbet Rag for Piano, 1992 (Box 34)
      - Fragment Rag for Piano 1992 (Box 34)
        (dedicated to W.A., signed by composer)
      - Fruhlinserwachen fur Viola, Vibraphon & Akkordeon, 1990 (Box 34)
      - G.P.-Rag: Ragtime for Piano, 1993 (Box 34)
      - Ingemisco-Lacrimosa: Fur gemischten Chor, Sopransolo, Baritonsolo und Orgel, circa 1991 (Box 34)
      - Kohelet's Lied fur Chor SATB, 1987 (Box 34)
      - Mir Ist Ein Schons Braun Meidelein fur gemischten Chor a cappella, 1990 (Box 34)
      - Missa Piccola pro nobis, 1995 (Box 34)
      - News from the New World: Collection of Pieces for Brass Quintet, 1991 (Box 34)
      - Parlando Curioso oder als Vorspeise: Buchstabensuppe nach Hexenart mit Einlagen fur Ausrufer und 2 Klaviere 1994 (Box 34)
      - Raindrops keep fallin' on my head (arrangement), 1990 (Box 34)
      - Sich Mahnen Erlost: Konzertstuck fur Blasorchester, 1989 (Box 34)
      - Szenen uber eine Eisenbahnfahrt fur Klavier solo, 1985 (Box 34)
      - Tango Tardo fur Klavier, 1988 (Box 34)
      - Tanz-Toccata fur Akkordeon solo, 1987 (Box 34)
      - 3 Capriccio's fur Saxophonquartett (SATB), copyright, 1990 (Box 34)
      - 3 Wiegenlieder fur Klavier, 1992 (Box 34)
      - Tocata non facile: Parodie fur 2 Klaviere, 1988 (Box 34)
        (annotated, signed by composer)
      - Toccata non facile: Parodie fur zwei Klaviere, 1988 (Box 34)
      - 2 Nocturnes fur mittlerestimee (alt), Klarinette und Klavierbegleitung, 1986 (Box 34)
    - Fry, James
      - Kaleidoscope for Bb Clarinet and Piano circa 1993 (Box 34)
    - Gandolfi, Michael
      - Points of Departure, 1988 (Box 34)
    - Gewidmet, Zsigmond Szathmary
      - Silben fur orgel, 1977 (Box 35)
        (annotated by composer [?])
    - Godfrey, Daniel
      - Mestengo for orchestra, 1988 (Box 35)
      - Numina, 1991 (Box 35)
      - Two Scenes in Chiaroscuro, copyright, 1994 (Box 35)
    - Golijov, Osvaldo
      - Balada de Ahogados Solitarios: two voices and four clarinets or three clarinets and two bass clarinets, undated (Box 35)
      - Yiddishbbuk: inscriptions for string quartet, circa 1992 (Box 35)
      - Yiddish Ruakh for clarinet and twelve instruments, 1990 (Box 35)
    - Gompper, David (student)
      - Do Not Go Gentle Into That Good Night for soprano, amplified piano and four percussion (by Dylan Thomas), 1989 (Box 35)
      - Quartet for violin, viola, violoncello and piano, 1996 (Box 35)
      - Shadows for organ and midi, 1996 (Box 35)
      - Trio for flute, violin and piano, 1989 (Box 35)
    - Gould, Gabriel Ian (student)
      - Fantasy on a Jewish Folktale for Violin and Piano, 1995 (Box 35)
    - Gottschalk, Arthur (student)
      - Blue Fantasy for Solo Violin and Chamber Orchestra, undated (Box 35)
      - Empire of the Sun for symphony orchestra, 1994 (Box 35)
      - Fakebook: Piano Solo, undated (Box 35)
      - Jeu du Chat for alto saxophone and piano 1981 (Box 35)
        (includes resume and list of works)
    - Grahn, Ulf
      - Looking forward to...(for Organ), 1972 (Box 35)
    - Gregg, Tom
      - A page from Symphony No.4, Mvt.2 by Charles Ives, 1981 (Box 35)
    - Gross, Robert
      - Executions on the Beach: An overture for orchestra, 1994 (Box 57)
      - Three Chamber Pieces, 1995 (Box 57)
    - Gryc, Stephen (student)
      - A Dance Concerto for clarinet and orchestra, copyright, 1989 (Box 35)
      - Kandinsky: Six Images for Organ, 1991 (Box 35)
      - Land of Steady Habits: A Slow Drag Two-Step, copyright, 1994 (Box 35)
      - Music for Tuba and Timpani, copyright, 1990 (Box 35)
      - Neon Night for orchestra copyright, 1985 (Box 50)
      - Pigs in Clover: A Classic Piano Rag, copyright, 1993 (Box 35)
      - Wind Machine for organ and orchestra, undated (Box 35)
    - Halle, John (student)
      - Austerity Measures for Orchestra, undated (Box 35)
    - Harris, Donald
      - Balladen for Piano, 1979 (Box 35)
      - Ludus: Chamber concerto for ten instruments, 1966 (Box 35)
    - Hartke, Stephen
      - Pacific Rim for orchestra, 1988 (Box 35)
    - Hartwell, Hugh
      - Piece for Piano, 1968 (Box 35)
    - Hasegawa, Ryo
      - Scherzando, circa 1994 (Box 35)
      - Autumn Breeze, circa 1994 (Box 35)
      - Untitled circa 1994 (Box 35)
      - Untitled circa 1994 (Box 35)
      - Untitled circa 1994 (Box 35)
    - Hause, Evan (student)
      - Chamber Symphony, 1994 (Box 35)
    - Hawkins, John
      - Waves for soprano & piano, 1971 (Box 36)
    - Hayes, Jeff (student)
      - Dark Songs for soprano and piano, 1991 (Box 36)
        (includes notes from composer)
      - Prismatic Variants: Theme and Ten Reflections for String Quartet, copyright, 1993 (Box 36)
      - Piano Trio, copyright, 1992 (Box 36)
      - String Quartet No.2 1988 (Box 36)
        (dedicated to W.A.; signed by composer)
    - Hershey, Sharon (student)
      - Arrival for soprano and orchestra (text by Adrienne Rich), 1992 (Box 50)
      - Bagatelle for Marimba and Flute, undated (Box 36)
      - Chapin for two marimbas undated (Box 57)
      - Duet for piano solo, undated (Box 57)
      - Idyll for marimba, mallets and violin, undated (Box 36)
      - Images for marimba, undated (Box 36)
      - Mother Ann Lee for Bb Bass/Eb Sop. Clarinet, Piano, and 2 Percussion, 1986 (Box 57)
      - Pianobook, undated (Box 57)
      - Psyche et l'Amore for Piano Trio 1984 (Box 50)
      - Songbook for woman's musical theatre voice, piano, harp, and percussion, undated (Box 57)
      - Vastness for 26 Instrumental Soloists, 1986 (Box 50)
    - Hertzog, Christian A.
      - Loops, undated (Box 36)
    - Hill, Augustus O
      - Psalm 91 for soprano, alto, tenor, baritone, and bass soli, mixed chorus and orchestra, copyright, 1992 (Box 36)
    - Hillebrandt, John (student)
      - Transcendental Hymn-Fantasies, undated (Box 36)
    - Hilmy, Steven Campbell
      - Lucifer in Starlight for flute, clarinet, viola, voice, two percussion and piano, 1989 (Box 36)
      - Shifting Thresholds: soprano, string quartet, percussion, piano, and tape (text by Samuel Beckett), 1994 (Box 36)
      - Sonata for Piano and Saxophone, 1987 (Box 36)
    - Hodkinson, Sydney
      - Publicity brochure undated (Box 36)
      - Arc: Aria with Interludes for soprano voice, flute-piccolo, piano, 2 percussion, 1969 (Box 36)
      - Armistice: A truce for dancers and musicians, 1966 (Box 36)
      - A Contemporary Primer for Band: A collection of musical studies for any number of wind and percussion players, 1972 (Box 36)
      - Interplay: a histrionic controversy for four musicians, 1966 (Box 36)
      - Lengeren for voice and double quintet (text by Alvin Greenberg) 1973 (Box 36)
      - A Little Ragchime Music for carillon, 1981 (Box 36)
      - Refractions for Solo Piano, 1965 (Box 36)
      - Ritual: A Procession for mixed chorus a cappella, 1970 (Box 36)
      - The Dissolution of the Serial or, Who Stole My Porridge? for piano and one instrument, 1967 (Box 36)
      - Tower for Concert Band, 1974 (Box 36)
      - And Yet: An elegy for SATB chorus with piano and optional handbells, 1984 (Box 36)
        (poem by Alvin Greenberg)
    - Hogan, Leslie (student)
      - Christmas Eve for SATB, unaccompanied (text by Robert Bridges), 1986 (Box 36)
      - Night Music for string orchestra, 1991 (Box 36)
      - Praise for orchestra, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Howrani, Waleed (Walid) (student)
      - Concerto for Alto Saxophone, Strings and Percussion, copyright, 1990 (Box 36)
      - Exotica for alto saxophone and piano, 1982 (Box 36)
    - Hurley, Susan
      - Wind River Songs for voice, piano, 'cello (poem by Nick Bozanic), 1988 (Box 36)
    - Humel, Gerhard
      - Untitled for piano 1981 (Box 37)
    - Ince, Denize (student)
      - Hava...(air...) for piano, 1988 (Box 37)
      - Iron Earth for orchestra, copyright, 1993 (Box 37)
      - Like, Like Not for solo piano, 1996 (Box 37)
      - Mixdown for two pianos, copyright, 1992 (Box 37)
    - Ince, Kamran
      - Publicity brochure undated (Box 37)
      - Before Infrared for orchestra, copyright, 1986 (Box 57)
      - Domes for orchestra, 1993 (Box 37)
      - Lipstick for orchestra 1990 (Box 37)
        (annotated by composer)
      - Waves of Talya for flute (piccolo), clarinet, piano, percussion, violin, violoncello, 1988 (Box 37)
    - Jaffe, Stephen
      - Concerto for Violin and Orchestra, undated (Box 37)
      - First Quartet, circa 1991 (Box 37)
      - Songs of Turning: Cantata for Soprano and Baritone Soloists, Chorus and Chamber Orchestra, copyright, 1996 (Box 37)
    - Janello, Mark (student)
      - Piano Trio for early instruments, 1990 (Box 37)
    - Jankowski, Loretta
      - Or: A Two Movement Work for Chamber Orchestra, 1976 (Box 50)
      - Orga, 1975 (Box 50)
    - Janson, Thomas
      - Rabbit's Revenge for Harp, 1972 (Box 37)
    - Jarvinen, Arthur
      - Serious Immobilities: 840 variations on Satie's Vexations for piano solo, 1997 (Box 37)
    - Jennings, Richard
      - Gnossos (a character sketch) (text by Richard Farina), undated (Box 37)
      - Nuolans for Piano, 1990 (Box 37)
      - Perspective: SATB Quartet or Choir (text by Sol Mandlsohn), 1991 (Box 37)
      - Portrait of Anne for Piano, 1992 (Box 37)
      - Three Tangier Poems: 3 Songs, Voice and Piano (text by Jack Kerouac), 1992 (Box 37)
    - Johnson, A. Paul
      - Little Suite for Piano, undated (Box 37)
    - Johnston, Donald O
      - The Throne of Jehovah for organ undated (Box 37)
    - Jones, Robert
      - Dembo...for piano solo, 1967 (Box 37)
      - Fisches Nachtgesang, 1969 (Box 37)
      - Three Piano Pieces, 1967 (Box 37)
    - Joyce, Donald
      - Autumn Cadences for organ 1979 (Box 37)
      - Rocking Piece for organ, 1978 (Box 37)
    - Kalbfleisch, Rodger C
      - Resurrection for organ, 1977 (Box 37)
    - Kalellis, Barrett
      - Necronomicon for piano, 1973 (Box 37)
    - Karpman, Laura (student)
      - Stanzas for Music: For High Voice and Chamber Ensemble (text by Lord Byron), undated (Box 51)
    - Kechley, David
      - In the Dragon's Garden for guitar and alto saxophone, copyright, 1992 (Box 37)
    - Kempf, Davorin
      - Prologue for organ and big orchestra, 1981 (Box 51)
    - Kernis, Aaron Jay
      - Suite in Three Parts for Solo Organ, 1983 (Box 37)
    - Kilstofte, Mark (student)
      - Quartette for string quartet, copyright, 1988 (Box 37)
    - Kincaid, Terrence
      - Untitled undated (Box 37)
    - Kirschenmann, Mark
      - Chop House for Trumpet and Marimba, 1993 (Box 58)
      - Elan Vital for Wind Ensemble, 1993 (Box 58)
      - Mutuality for Violin and Cello, 1993 (Box 58)
      - Paradigm Shift for String Quartet and Soprano Sax, 1992 (Box 58)
    - Kirshner, Andy (student)
      - Poet's Love (a Jazz Song Cycle), copyright, 1995 (Box 51)
    - Klausmeyer, Peter
      - The Conservative: A Piece in Two Movements for String Quartet, 1976 (Box 51)
      - The Hound of Morrisville for organ, 1976 (Box 37)
      - Three Songs on Poems of Dorothy Parker for piano and solo soprano, 1987 (Box 37)
    - Knussen
      - Symphony No.3 for large orchestra, 1979 (Box 38)
    - Koblitz, David
      - Le Cru et le Cuit (The Raw and the Cooked) for alto flute/piccolo, Bb clarinet/bass clarinet, cello, piano and percussion, 1979 (Box 38)
      - Lobo: oboe (English horn), violin, mandolin, piano, 1971 (Box 58)
    - Kolesnikow, Rama (student)
      - Mother, undated (Box 58)
    - Kovalio, Iris
      - Fifteen Short Piano Pieces for children or beginners, 1986 (Box 38)
    - Kramer, Jonathon
      - Music for Piano, Number 4, 1972 (Box 38)
      - The Sunrise Sonata for two-manual harpsichord, 1985 (Box 38)
    - Kramer, Timothy
      - Colors from a Changing Sky for piano solo 1994 (Box 38)
      - Concerto for Organ and Orchestra, 1994 (Box 38)
      - A Fivescore Festival for orchestra, 1990 (Box 38)
      - Perceptions of Antiquity for organ, 1983 (Box 38)
    - Kremen, Israel
      - Peace Symphony for Tenor and Symphony Orchestra, 1989 (Box 38)
        (University of Michigan dissertation, includes abstract)
    - Kurtz, Eugene
      - Animations for piano 1968 (Box 38)
        (dedicated to Sarah and W. Albright; signed by composer; annotated)
      - Ca..., diagramme pour orchestre, 1972 (Box 38)
      - Five-Sixteen pour piano, 1982 (Box 38)
    - Kurtz, Mark
      - Abreaction 1989 for piano, 1989 (Box 38)
      - Advent for orchestra, undated (Box 38)
      - Essay for Chamber Orchestra, copyright, 1992 (Box 38)
      - Mechanical Action for organ, circa 1990 (Box 38)
    - Laibman, Joseph Alan
      - Counterpoint I: Homage to Bach for organ, strings and eight trombones, 1988 (Box 58)
    - Lafford, Lindsay
      - Magnificat and Nunc Dimittis Gwasanaeth Dewi Sant (The St. David's Service) For Male Voices (ATB) and Organ, 1995 (Box 38)
      - Minuetto Volcae for organ, 1995 (Box 38)
    - Lavenda, Richard
      - Balancing Act for violin and piano, 1993 (Box 38)
    - Leitch, Larry
      - The Entrance, 1966-1970 (Box 38)
      - Fancy Free or It's There: An obstacle illusion program (Illusion model IV), 1970 (Box 38)
    - Lentini, James
      - Montage for Piano Trio, copyright, 1992 (Box 38)
      - Music for Brass, copyright, 1983 (Box 38)
      - Symphony No.1 (Two Movements for Orchestra), copyright, 1990 (Box 38)
    - Levin, Rami (student)
      - A New Leaf for basset clarinet and tape, 1990 (Box 38)
      - Conversation Piece: suite for piano duet, 1987 (Box 38)
      - Fanfare for 2 trumpets, copyright, 1989 (Box 38)
    - Levin, Todd (student)
      - Aqua Vitae for solo marimba and 17 musicians, undated (Box 38)
      - Vanishing Hearts, undated (Box 51)
    - Levin, T. Bennett
      - Peter Quince at the Clavier for orchestra, 1982 (Box 38)
    - Levy, Matthew
      - Under the Sun: Concerto Grosso for Four Midi Wind Controllers and String Orchestra, undated (Box 39)
    - Ligetti, Gyorgy
      - Etude 12: L'Escalier du Diable, 1993 (Box 58)
    - Lindroth, Scott
      - Clash and Glitter: Scenes of Barbaric Splendor for Orchestra, 1989 (Box 39)
    - Locklair, Dan
      - Jubilate Deo (O Be Joyful in the Lord) for choir (satb), organ, brass, and percussion (opt.), 1979 (Box 39)
    - Lovinfosse, Dennis
      - Studies in Textures and Colors for Organ, Two Pianos, Vibraphone and Marimba, 1981 (Box 39)
    - Lubetsky, Ronald
      - Sonnet Cycle: settings to poetry by Petrarch, Shakespeare, Mallarme, Rilke for medium-high voice, alto flute (piccolo), oboe, clarinet, two percussion, piano, harp, 'cello, 1980 (Box 39)
    - Luce, Greg
      - Diamondback Rag, copyright, 1980 (Box 39)
      - Lithia Rag: A Classy Rag, copyright, 1980 (Box 39)
      - Echoes in Ragtime, copyright, 1980 (Box 39)
      - Blackjack Rag, copyright, 1980 (Box 39)
      - Crystal Set Rag, copyright, 1980 (Box 39)
      - Applesauce Rag, copyright, 1974 (Box 39)
      - Sunset Rag, copyright, 1974 (Box 39)
    - Luedeke, Raymond
      - Fancies and Interludes V for violoncello and organ, 1984 (Box 39)
    - Maddox, Arthur
      - Bridal Bouquet, 1993 (Box 39)
      - A Miscellany of Old-style Stuff: composed or transcribed/adapted (and foisted off on William Albright) 1995 (Box 39)
      - Obnazonym Nogom (to legs laid bare) for piano, 1972 (Box 39)
      - 3 Piano Rags, 1992 (Box 39)
      - Wistful Waltz (Theme from Ed's Co-Ed): Piano Solo, copyright, 1990 (Box 39)
    - Mather, Bruce
      - Music for Organ, Horn and Gongs, 1973 (Box 39)
      - Six Etudes pour Orgue, 1983 (Box 39)
    - McBride, Eugene
      - The Glass of Life for tenor and piano, 1994 (Box 39)
    - McKinley, William T
      - Paintings #2, 1975 (Box 51)
    - McKinley, Elliott Miles
      - April for orchestra 1994 (Box 51)
    - Mead, Andrew
      - Concerto for Alto Saxophone and Eleven Players, 1993 (Box 39)
    - Meister, Chris
      - Box Music for flute, oboe, clarinet, trumpet, bassoon and percussion 1982 (Box 39)
      - Herbert Hoover Heever for two soprano, chorus, percussion and vacuum cleaners, 1982 (Box 39)
      - sprinklings of stars harbor streams of streaming sky dragons for string quartet, undated (Box 39)
    - Messiaen, Olivier
      - Ile de Feu 1 pour Piano, 1950 (Box 39)
      - Ile de Feu 2 pour Piano, 1950 (Box 39)
      - Mode de Valeurs et d'Intensites pour Piano, 1949 (Box 39)
      - Neumes Rythmiques pour Piano, 1949 (Box 39)
    - Middleton, Robert
      - 4 Organ Preludes, 1956 (Box 39)
    - Milburn, Ellsworth
      - Character Pieces: Cello and Piano, 1980 (Box 39)
      - Chiaroscuro for orchestra, 1984 (Box 39)
      - Spiritus Mundi: mezzo-soprano, five instrumentalists, and conductor (poems by C.E. Cooper), 1974 (Box 39)
      - String Quartet, 1974 (Box 39)
    - Moravec, Paul
      - Circular Dreams for Clarinet, Violin, Cello and Piano, 1991 (Box 39)
      - Inscape for flute, clarinet (bass clarinet), violin, violoncello, percussion and piano, copyright, 1996 (Box 39)
      - Music Remembers: piano solo, 1985 (Box 39)
      - Northern Lights Electric for Flute, Clarinet, Piano, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello and Bass, 1994 (Box 39)
      - Sempre Diritto! (Straight Ahead!) for Chamber Orchestra, 1992 (Box 39)
      - Sonata for Violin and Piano, 1992 (Box 39)
      - Spiritdance: Orchestra, 1989 (Box 51)
    - Morrill, Dexter
      - Fantasy Quintet for Piano and Computer, copyright, 1978 (Box 39)
      - Six Dark Questions for soprano and computer, copyright, 1979 (Box 39)
    - Morris, Robert
      - Allies for piano, four hands, 1979 (Box 51)
      - Cairn for piano, 1968 (Box 40)
      - Continua for orchestra (incomplete?), undated (Box 58)
      - Four Fold Heart Sutra, for solo baritone, male chorus, vibraphone, piano, 1984 (Box 40)
      - Head for piano solo, undated (Box 51)
      - Phases for two pianos [with photo-cell mixers], 1970 (Box 40)
      - Rapport for live electronic instruments, undated (Box 40)
      - Sangita '67 for flutes, percussion and strings, undated (Box 40)
      - Throughout (Anyway) for four flutes, 1975 (Box 40)
      - Tournament for trombone choir, 1981 (Box 51)
      - Trip for piano solo, undated (Box 40)
      - Variations on the Variation of the Quadran Pavan and the Quadran Paban by Bull and Byrd for two pianos, 1974 (Box 40)
    - Morrison, John Howell (student)
      - Excursive Sonata for thirteen musicians, 1988 (Box 40)
      - Hear What the Earth Says: for orchestra, undated (Box 51)
      - My Love Lives Down That Long Dirt Road: for Harpsichord, 1992 (Box 40)
    - Neil, William
      - A Play of Poems for soprano, bass-baritone and orchestra, 1984 (Box 40)
    - Neilson, Duncan (student)
      - Andromeda Baby for mezzo-soprano, theremin, and chamber orchestra (, 1998 (Box 52)
        University of Michigan master's thesis; includes notes from composer)
    - Nelson, Brian (student)
      - Mandala for orchestra, copyright, 1990 (Box 40)
    - Nelson, Larry
      - Music of Twelve Centers for piano, copyright, 1981 (Box 58)
    - Needles, Jim Warren (student)
      - Octet for double string quartet, 1980 (Box 52)
      - Plexus for orchestra 1983 (Box 40)
        (University of Michigan dissertation)
    - Newby, Stephen Michael
      - Symphony: Let Thy Mercy Be Upon Us A Tribute to Martin Luther King Jr. for orchestra, choir and tenor solo 1994 (Box 40)
    - Nichols, David J
      - Rolling Thunder for piano, 1988 (Box 40)
      - Songs of the Drum: A duet for two pianists, featuring 15 songs of the Ojibway Indians, 1988 (Box 40)
    - Noda, Ryo
      - Improvisation 1 pour saxophone alto seul, 1972 (Box 40)
    - Nordensten, Frank Tveor
      - Tunnels for piano, 1980 (Box 52)
    - Opel, Doug (student)
      - Dilukkenjon for orchestra, 1993 (Box 40)
    - Palmer, Glenn (student)
      - Concertino for Orchestra, 1989 (Box 52)
    - Pann, Carter (student)
      - Dance Partita for small orchestra, 1995 (Box 40)
        (University of Michigan master's thesis; includes note from composer)
      - Deux Sejours for orchestra, 1994 (Box 40)
      - Two Portraits of Barcelona, 1994 (Box 40)
    - Pape, Gerard
      - Battle: Scene de Weaveworld pour quatre voix solos et bande, 1996 (Box 40)
      - Le Fleuve du Desir, 1994 (Box 52)
    - Peck, Russell
      - In the Garden of Gethsemane for organ undated (Box 40)
    - Pehrson, Joseph (student)
      - Etheroscape for Eight Flutes, 1989 (Box 40)
    - Perera, Ronald
      - Reverberations for organ, 1970 (Box 40)
        (signed by composer[?])
    - Perone, James
      - Canon for Saxophone Quartet, 1988 (Box 40)
    - Phan, Phuc Q. (student)
      - Flash for chamber orchestra, 1994 (Box 52)
      - Home-Cookin' for chamber orchestra, 1991 (Box 40)
      - Immortal Fragments for large orchestra, 1991 (Box 40)
      - Kiteflute for solo flute and two pianos, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Son Tinh and Thuy Tinh 1993 (Box 52)
    - Phipps, Karen (student)
      - The Captured Goddess for SATB choir and keyboard (poem by Amy Lowell), copyright, 1989 (Box 41)
      - Country Reflections: A Song Cycle for voice and piano, copyright, 1985 (Box 41)